KHOA V.D HUYNH

714-989-9331 | kaohulogist@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/khoa-vd-huynh | https://github.com/kaohulogist

Goodyear, 85338 | Willing to relocate (U.S. Citizenship)

An Electrical Engineer candidate with comprehensive experience in plant automated control systems consisting of electro-mechanical components, sensors, pneumatics, and drive systems. Proficient in CAD design, system integration, troubleshooting, and project management. An eager-to-learn, energetic prospect dedicated to enhancing mutual growth with the company.

SKILLS:

- Industrial Automation: PLC, HMI, SCADA, Allen Bradley, Siemens TIA Portal V17, RFID, 3D AutoCAD, Multisim
- Teamwork; Ethical; Attention to Detail; Bilingual, Problem Solving, Time Management.
- Programming & Data: SQL databases, Python, C++, Visual Basic, Machine Learning, Bash, Matlab
- I.T: AWS, Security+, Linux, Container, Kubernetes, Terraform, Citrix, Remedy
- Documentation: Drafted Design Specifications, Test Plans, and Engineering Reports.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE:

Humana, Phoenix, AZ

12/2022 - present

(Automation Pharmacy Engineering Technician)

- Utilized hand and power tools for regular preventative maintenance, inspections, and repairs.
- Supported the development of equipment and system designs to achieve 50,000 prescription orders daily.
- Conducted root cause analysis to eliminate malfunctions, reduce cost, and improve quality.
- Ensured drug distribution reliability to target machine downtime under 3%.
- Worked on AC/DC motors and motor controls under a 3-phase 480V electric and electrical equipment environment.
- Installed production lines including PLC, conveyors, pneumatic, electronics, 80/20, controllers, and I/O systems.
- Familiarity with vendors Flexlink, SureKap, LDU Tension, Hydro, NPI, AutoBagger, Hydro, QMSI, Edge Water.

NASA Texas Space Grant Consortium Design Challenge

09/2021-06/2022

Vehicle Interchangeable Electronic Controller (VIEC) Network System

(HEC5 Team – Technical Design System Lead)

- Designed and implemented a system of interchangeable controllers to interact with multiple sensors (analog & digital) for automation, executing the appropriate program based on a positional identifier.
- Used CAD software to create prototypes and developed a Python-based GUI for the Raspberry Pi microprocessor.
- Successfully developed a highly reliable product with a swapping rate above 95%, all within a budget of \$1000.

U.S. Department of Commerce, Katy, TX

05/2020 - 11/2020

(IT Support)

- Managed the remote deployment of OS patches and updates to avoid service and resolve technical issues.
- Applied information security protocols to oversee account credentials and directed the need to higher-level support.

Vinny AC, Houston, TX

06/2021 - 08/2022

(AC Technician Associate)

- Diagnosed and repaired electrical and mechanical faults in residential HVAC systems.
- Communicated issues and cost estimates with clients, ensuring high-quality service delivery.

US Jaclean, Houston, TX

05/2016 - 09/2019

(Manager)

- Managed daily operations in sales, covering vending, retail, and wholesale channels.
- Led a team of 10, coordinating project deadlines, and ensuring successful product distribution.

Teacup (Coffee Shop) | **9Cstudio** (Photography & videography) (**Business Owner**)

01/2015 - present

Graduated: 06/2022

- Oversaw day-to-day operations and growth strategies and took proactive measures to ensure the business thrived.
- Built a loyal customer base through consistent quality and service excellence commitment.

EDUCATION:

The University of Texas at Tyler, Houston, TX

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering (BSEE)